Guide to the Burton White Papers, 1983-1994 CTC.1992.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Burton White Papers
1983-1994
CTC.1992.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
4.5 linear feet (8 boxes)
Burton White was a stage manager, consultant, and producer for several different Pittsburgh theatre production companies in the 1980's. These papers reflect the early professional career of Burton White and consist of production books and notes, mostly from productions in the Pittsburgh area.
White, Burton
Biography
Burton White was a stage manager, consultant, and producer for several different Pittsburgh theatre production companies in the 1980's. Among the companies he worked with were the Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival, the Pittsburgh Playhouse, the University of Pittsburgh Theatre Arts Department, the Pittsburgh Savoyards, and the Opera Theatre of Pittsburgh. One notable variation was a production of Dreamgirls produced by the American Theatre Company in Hawaii which included several cast members who would go on to Miss Saigon on Broadway. In 1989, White produced Joseph and the Technicolor Dreamcoat with Ken Gargaro under the name Gargaro Productions. Among the notable persons Burton White has worked with are: Ken Gargaro of the Pittsburgh Playhouse and Gargaro Productions, Jerry Herman of the Pittsburgh Playhouse and the production of the American Theatre's production of Dreamgirls, Tony Aguilar of Dreamgirls, Nicolas Pennell of the Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival, and Mildred Miller Posvar of the Pittsburgh Opera Theatre.
Arrangement
This collection is divided into two series. All production books are cross referenced in the Curtis Collection's Acting Edition and Script Inventory.
Series I. Career
Series II. Productions
Scope and Content Notes
These papers reflect the early professional career of Burton White and consist of production books and notes, mostly from productions in the Pittsburgh area.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These records were received as a gift of Burton White in July 1992 and in 1999.
Previous Citation
Burton White Papers, 1983-1994, CTC.1992.04, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Burton White Papers, 1983-1994, CTC.24, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Opera Theatre of Pittsburgh.; Pittsburgh Playhouse.; Pittsburgh Public Theater.; Pittsburgh Savoyards.; Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival (Pittsburgh, Pa.).; University of Pittsburgh. Department of Theatre Arts.; University of Pittsburgh. University Theatre.; White, Burton; Performing arts -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Stage management; Stage managers -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Theater; Theater -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Theater -- Production and direction
- Career, I.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains items that apply to White's career in theatre, but not to specific productions on which he worked. They include interviews with local papers, reviews for local papers, correspondence, and one research file on Bob Fosse.
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bob Fosse (White's personal research file) (Folder 2)
  - Interviews with Burton White, 1985-1986 (Folder 3-4)
  - Resignation from Pittsburgh Playhouse, July 3, 1986 (Folder 5)
  - Local theatre reviews by Burton White for the Pitt News, 1984 (Folder 6-7)
- Productions, II.
  This series of files relates to the numerous productions of which Burton White was a part. The files, arranged alphabetically by title, contain production scripts, notes, programs, stage manager's books, newspaper clippings, and musical scores.
  - American Theatre Company of Hawaii, 1.
    - Dreamgirls - American Theatre Company of Hawaii, 1989 (Folder 8-10)
    - Dreamgirls - American Theatre Company of Hawaii, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1-9)
  - Carnegie Mellon University Drama, 2.
    - Two Women - by Lisa Humbertson 1st Prize Bud Yorkin Playwrighting Contest, Carnegie Mellon University, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Gargaro Productions, 3.
    - Bye Bye Birdie - Gargaro Productions, 1994 (Folder 2-6)
    - Joseph and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat - Gargaro Productions, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
    - Joseph and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat - instrumental music, 1989 (Cassette 1)
    - Jesus Christ Superstar (Folder 4)
  - Great American Melodrama & Vaudeville, 4.
    - Cinderella, or, the Show Must Go On - Great American Melodrama & Vaudeville, 1988 (Folder 5)
    - Dead Pan Lost - Great American Melodrama & Vaudeville (Folder 6)
    - The Perils of Pismo Peg - Great American Melodrama & Vaudeville, 1989 (Folder 7)
  - Pittsburgh Opera Theater, 5.
    - Orfeo and Euridice - Pittsburgh Opera Theater, 1990 (Folder 8-10)
  - Pittsburgh Playhouse, 6.
    - A Chorus Line - Pittsburgh Playhouse, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
    - Godspell - Pittsburgh Playhouse, 1986 (Folder 7-8)
    - Jesus Christ Superstar, 1985, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater, 7.
    - Night of the Iguana - Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1989 (Folder 2)
  - Pittsburgh Savoyards, 8.
    - Princess Ida - Pittsburgh Savoyards, 1984 (Folder 3-7)
  - Robert Morris Colonial Theatre, 9.
    - Roar of the Greasepaint - Robert Morris Colonial Theatre (Folder 8)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival, 10.
    - No Holds Bard - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival, 1983 (Folder 9)
    - Tammy Grimes - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - A Variable Passion - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival, 1985 (Folder 2-5)
  - University of Pittsburgh Theatre Arts Department, 11.
    - Good/Windows of Heaven - University of Pittsburgh Theatre Arts and the Jewish Playwrights Conference, 1983 (Folder 6)
    - On Broadway - University of Pittsburgh Theatre Arts (Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous and Unidentified Productions, 12.
    - Unidentified production notes (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Hair - commercial score (Folder 2)
    - Leader of the Pack, 1985 (Folder 3)
    - Pittsburgh Brewing Company - 125th Anniversary Project (Folder 4)